<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>matt lebrun - health</title><link href="https://blog.mattlebrun.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.mattlebrun.com/feeds/blog.mattlebrun.com.health.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.mattlebrun.com/</id><updated>2018-06-24T16:44:00+08:00</updated><subtitle>in between code, coffee, and peanut butter.</subtitle><entry><title>getting into cycling</title><link href="https://blog.mattlebrun.com/2018/06/getting-into-cycling.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-06-24T16:44:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-06-24T16:44:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Matt Lebrun</name></author><id>tag:blog.mattlebrun.com,2018-06-24:/2018/06/getting-into-cycling.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're like me, you probably had your on-and-off bouts using a bicycle.
Perhaps you even thought it's not meant for you. However, life changes …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're like me, you probably had your on-and-off bouts using a bicycle.
Perhaps you even thought it's not meant for you. However, life changes, Manila
traffic got worst, and I wanted to break away from being sedentary. So here
I am with a renewed interest in using a bicycle to commute, go places, and have
fun adventures with my family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a couple of challenges with this -- not having a bike and not having
enough experience in using a bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="finding-the-the-right-bike"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;finding the the right bike&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first problem, &lt;em&gt;not having a bike&lt;/em&gt;, should be easy enough to solve. Just
buy a bike! But this comes with a sub-problem -- &lt;em&gt;where to store the bike&lt;/em&gt;.
This is a problem when your living in a 23sqm home. The solution: a folding bike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-nyfti-folding-bike"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;the Nyfti folding bike&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a kid, I've always thought a folding bike is such a cool thing to have. I
saw this video a few years ago that really made me yearn for one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row section-bot"&gt;
   &lt;div class="col-lg-2 col-md-0 col-sm-0"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;div class="col-lg-8 col-md-12 col-sm-12"&gt;
      &lt;div class="mx-auto d-block"&gt;
           &lt;iframe id="player" type="text/html"
               width="100%" height="480"
               src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/txi2zIjDG3Q?&amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;origin="
               frameborder=0&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bicycle featured in this video is the original &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nyftibicycles.strikingly.com/"&gt;Nyfti&lt;/a&gt; folding bike. It is
a Filipino-made bike that has a very small folding dimension. It made me dream
of travelling places with a bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="experiencing-a-nyfti-ride-for-the-first-time"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;experiencing a Nyfti ride for the first time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last May 2018, I decided to pay the Nyfti workshop a visit. I met Carl Mamawal,
co-founder and CEO, and he had me try one of the bikes for a spin. I was
instantly hooked at how easy the riding and handling of the bike was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Talking to Carl about the Nyfti bike" class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block zenm-media-max section-bot align-center" src="/static/images/getting-into-cycling-000.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later he asked me what did I plan to use the bike for. I told him I would
use it to commute to my work place in BGC, then perhaps when I'm more skilled,
I'd take it for touring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He offered to give me and Mickey a bike tour from Makati to BGC using a couple
of his demo bikes to show us a good route in and out of BGC. How cool is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="my-first-12km-riding-a-bike"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;my first 12km riding a bike&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met again a few weeks later at his place and set off to Mickey and I's
very first long-ish bike ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the Nyfti bikes we used to get to BGC. It was my first time cycling
across EDSA or cycling for more than a kilometer really. It was scary, thrilling
and just an overall fun experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nyfti test drive Makati-BGC 2" class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block zenm-media-max section-bot align-center" src="/static/images/getting-into-cycling-002.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carl is a pretty cool guy. He was very patient and accomodating in guiding
a couple of noobs like us. He got us through EDSA and in and out of BGC safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="getting-my-very-own-nyfti-bike"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;getting my very own Nyfti bike&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to June 2018, I am now a proud and happy owner of a Nyfti Raio v2!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nyfti Raio v2 proud owner" class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block zenm-media-max section-bot align-center" src="/static/images/getting-into-cycling-003.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second problem, &lt;em&gt;where to store the bike&lt;/em&gt;, is solved as it fits perfectly
into a small space too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Nyfti Raio v2 perfect fit" class="img-fluid mx-auto d-block zenm-media-max section-bot align-center" src="/static/images/getting-into-cycling-004.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I've already taken it out for a few rides which I will be
talking about soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="nyfti"></category><category term="cycling"></category></entry><entry><title>4 weeks to fitness experiment</title><link href="https://blog.mattlebrun.com/2014/01/4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-02T17:48:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-01-02T17:48:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Matt Lebrun</name></author><id>tag:blog.mattlebrun.com,2014-01-02:/2014/01/4-weeks-to-fitness-experiment.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A healthy programmer, is an effective programmer.&lt;br&gt;
- me (when deciding to write this post)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my key goals for this year is to get …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A healthy programmer, is an effective programmer.&lt;br&gt;
- me (when deciding to write this post)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my key goals for this year is to get in to the habit of keeping myself 
healthy. I believe its in our best interest as software engineers to have a 
balanced lifestlye to ensure that we are always working to the best of our 
abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since April of last year I've started feeling my way towards adding regular 
exercises as part of my weekly activities. I make sure that I do something to 
get my blood pumping at least once a week. While I've not been emperically 
tracking the effects of these efforts, It just feels good to get some 
adrenaline rush every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, my body fat percentage did became normal which was a first!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I decided to take things up a notch for this month in the efforts of 
making this habit stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be following a 
&lt;a href="http://www.lulu.com/shop/daniel-segars-and-kelli-segars/low-impact-4-week-fat-loss-program-for-beginners/ebook/product-21250586.html"&gt;4-week program&lt;/a&gt; 
set up by the awesome folks at &lt;a href="http://www.fitnessblender.com/"&gt;Fitness Blender&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;s&gt;I'll be doing a weekly update of my progress here and see how it goes.&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;update&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst I've been lazy about documenting my 4-week experimentation, I can tell you that I've had
phenomenal results following the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I've developed a habit of regular exercise and is now part of my weekly routine. I've
also tried out other exercise practices lately such as HIIT and the 7-minute workout to great effect
as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now starting a new fitness program which I'll be writing about soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="fitness"></category></entry></feed>